<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<!-- This document was created with Syntext Serna Free. --><!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="chap-Release_Notes-Key_Features">
  <title>Key Features</title>
  <para>This section describes the key features available in Red Hat Storage. The following is a list of feature highlights of this new version of the Red Hat  Storage software: </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">High Availability</emphasis></para>
      <para>The Red Hat  Storage provides both synchronous and asynchronous n-way file replication to assure data availability:</para>
      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Synchronous replication</emphasis> provides redundancy and protection within a single data center or multiple data centers and availability zones in a region.</para>
          </listitem>
          <listitem>
            <para><emphasis role="bold">Asynchronous geo-replication</emphasis>-  Red Hat Storage supports Geo-Rep long distance replication. Customers can configure storage server nodes and Red Hat Storage to asynchronously replicate data
over vast geographical distances.
.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Deploy in Minutes</emphasis></para>
      <para>The Red Hat  Storage S can be deployed in minutes, providing one of the fastest ways to create an on-demand, high-performance, petabyte-scale storage environment. </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">No Application Rewrites</emphasis></para>
      <para>Red Hat   Storage Appliance provides full support for the semantics of a normal Linux file system like ext4 so there is no need to rewrite applications when moving data to the cloud as with cloud-based object storage. </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Flexibility</emphasis>
</para>
      <para>Runs in userspace, eliminating the need for complex
kernel patches or dependencies.
</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Scalability</emphasis>
</para>
      <para>Elastic volume management enables storage volumes
to be abstracted from the hardware so data and hardware can be managed independently. Storage can be
added while data continues to be available, with no
application interruption. Volumes can grow across
machines in the system and can be migrated within the
system to rebalance capacity. Storage server nodes
can be added on the fly.
</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">Simple Management</emphasis>
</para>
      <para>Simple, single command for storage management. It also includes performance monitoring and analysis tools like Top and Profile. Top provides visibility into the workload pattern and Profile provides performance
statistics over a user-defined
time period for metrics including latency and amount of
data read or written.
</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para><emphasis role="bold">No Metadata Server </emphasis></para>
      <para>Rather than using a centralized or
distributed metadata server, Red Hat Storage software
 uses an elastic hashing algorithm to locate
data in the storage pool removing this common source
of I/O bottlenecks and vulnerability to failure. Data
access is fully parallelized and performance scales
linearly.
</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</chapter>
